在第一课中，我们将涵盖模型、提示和解析器。
In lesson one, we'll be covering models, prompts, and parsers.
因此，模型是指支撑许多内容的语言模型。
So models refers to the language models underpinning a lot of it.
提示是指创建输入以传递到模型的样式。
Prompts refers to the style of creating inputs to pass into the models.
然后解析器位于相反的端点。
And then parsers is on the opposite end.
它涉及将这些模型的输出解析为更结构化的格式，以便您可以在下游执行操作。
It involves taking the output of these models and parsing it into a more
因此，当您使用llm构建应用程序时，
structured format so that you can do things downstream with it.
它们通常是可重用的模型。
So when you build a application using an llm,
我们反复提示模型，
they'll often be reusable models.
解析输出，因此Lanchain提供了一组易于使用的抽象来执行此类操作。
We repeatedly prompt a model,
因此，让我们开始看一下模型、提示和解析器。
parses outputs, and so Lanchain gives
因此，为了开始，
an easy set of abstractions to do this type of operation.
这里有一些起始代码。
So with that, let's jump in and take a look at models, prompts, and parsers.
我要导入OS，
So to get started,
导入OpenAI，并加载我的OpenAI秘钥。
here's a little bit of starter code.
OpenAI库已经安装在
I'm going to import OS,
我的Jupyter笔记本环境中，因此如果您在本地运行此代码，
import OpenAI, and load my OpenAI secret key.
并且您尚未安装OpenAI，
The OpenAI library is already installed in
您可能需要运行它。
my Jupyter notebook environment so if you're running this locally,
BangPip install OpenAI，但我不会在这里这样做。
and you don't have OpenAI installed yet,
然后这是一个辅助函数。
you might need to run that.
这实际上与您可能在
BangPip install OpenAI, but I'm not going to do that here.
ChatGPT提示工程师开发者课程中看到的辅助函数非常相似，
And then here's a helper function.
所以使用这个辅助函数，
This is actually, um,
您可以说get completion on，
very similar to the helper function that you might have seen in
什么是1加1，这将调用ChatGPT或技术上的模型，
the chatGPT prompt engineering for developers course
GPT 3.5 Turbo，以便您可以得到这样的答案。
that I offered together with OpenAI's user forfeit.
因此，为了激发模型提示和解析器的线链抽象，
And so with this helper function,
让我们假设您收到一封来自客户的电子邮件，该电子邮件不是英语。
you can say get completion on,
为了确保这是可访问的，我将使用英语海盗语言。
um, what is 1 plus 1 and this will call chatGPT or technically the model,
当客户说R时，
GPT 3.5 Turbo to give you an answer back like this.
我会因为搅拌机盖子飞出去，把我的厨房墙壁弄得满是果汁而感到愤怒。
Now, to motivate the line chain abstractions for model prompts and parsers,
更糟糕的是，保修不包括清洁厨房的费用。
um, let's say you get an email from a customer in a language other than English.
我现在需要你的帮助，伙计。
Um, in order to make sure this is accessible,
所以我们将要做的是请求这个LLM以平静和尊重的口吻将文本翻译成美式英语。
the other language I'm going to use is the English pirate language.
所以我将把风格设置为平静和尊重的美式英语。
When the customer says, R,
为了实现这一点，我将使用一个f字符串来指定提示和指令。
I'd be fuming that me blender lid flew off and splatted my kitchen walls with smoothie.
如果你之前看过一些提示，我将使用一个f字符串来指定提示和指令。
And to make matters worse, the warranty don't cover the cost of cleaning up me kitchen.
我将指定用三个反引号括起来的文本翻译成指定的风格。
I need your help right now, matey.
然后插入这两种风格。
And so what we will do is ask this LLM to
这样就生成了一个提示，说要翻译文本等等。
translate the text to American English in a calm and respectful tone.
我鼓励你暂停视频并运行代码，尝试修改提示以查看是否可以获得不同的输出。
So I'm going to set style to American English in a calm and respectful tone.
然后，你可以提示大型语言模型以获得响应。
And so in order to actually accomplish this,
让我们看看响应是什么。
if you've seen a little bit of prompting before,
说将英语海盗的消息翻译成这个非常礼貌的语气。
I'm going to specify the prompt using an f-string with the instructions,
我真的很沮丧，因为我的搅拌机盖子飞了出去，
translate the text that is delimited by triple backticks into style that is style.
把我的厨房墙壁弄得满是果汁等等。
And then plug in these two styles.
嗯，我现在真的需要你的帮助，我的朋友。听起来非常好。
And so this generates a prompt that says translate the text and so on.
因此，如果你有不同语言的不同客户撰写评论，
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code and also
不仅仅是英语海盗，还有法语、德语、日语等等，
try modifying the prompt to see if you can get a different output.
你可以想象需要生成一整个提示序列来生成这样的翻译。
You can then, um,
让我们看看如何使用Lang chain更方便地完成这项工作。
prompt the large language model to get a response.
我将导入chat open AI。这是Lang chain对chat GPT API端点的抽象。
Let's see what the response is.
因此，如果我设置chat等于chat open AI并查看chat是什么，
Says translated the English pirates message into this very polite,
它将创建这个对象，使用chat GPT模型，也称为GPT 3.5 turbo。
I'm really frustrated that my blender lid flew off and made
当我构建应用程序时，
a mess of my kitchen walls with smoothie and so on.
我经常做的一件事是将温度参数设置为0。
Um, I could really use your help right now my friend. That sounds very nice.
所以默认温度为0.7。
So if you have different customers writing reviews in different languages,
但让我重新设置温度为0.0。
not just English pirate, but French, German, Japanese, and so on,
现在将温度设置为0，以使我们输出的随机性稍微减少一些。
you can imagine having to generate
现在让我按如下方式定义模板字符串。
a whole sequence of prompts to generate such translations.
将由三个向量分隔的文本翻译成样式。
Let's look at how we can do this in a more convenient way using Lang chain.
然后这里是文本。
I'm going to import chat open AI.
为了反复重用这个模板，
This is Lang chain's abstraction for the chat GPT API endpoint.
让我们导入Lang chain的聊天提示模板。
And so if I then set chat equals chat open AI and look at what chat is,
然后让我使用我们刚刚编写的模板字符串创建一个提示模板。
it creates this object, um,
从提示模板中，
as follows that uses the chat GPT model,
你实际上可以提取原始提示，并意识到
which is also called GPT 3.5 turbo.
这个提示有两个输入变量，样式和文本，
When I'm building applications,
这些用花括号表示。
one thing I will often do is set the temperature parameter to be equal to 0.
这里也是我们指定的原始模板。
So the default temperature is 0.7.
事实上，如果我打印出来，
But let me actually redo that with temperature equals 0.0.
它意识到它有两个输入变量，样式和文本。
And now the temperature is set to 0 to make us output a little bit less random.
现在让我们指定样式。
And now let me define the template string as follows.
这是我想要的样式，
Translate the text delimited by triple vectors into style that is style.
将客户消息翻译成该样式。
And then here's the text.
所以我要称之为客户样式。
And to repeatedly reuse this template,
这是我之前的同一个客户电子邮件。
let's import Lang chain's chat prompt template.
现在，如果我创建
And then let me create a prompt template using that template string that we just wrote above.
客户消息，这将生成提示，
From the prompt template,
并将在一分钟内传递给大型语言模型以获得响应。
you can actually extract the original prompt and it realizes that
所以如果你想看看类型，
this prompt has two input variables, the style and the text,
客户消息实际上是一个列表。
which were, um, shown here with the curly braces.
如果你看一下列表的第一个元素，
And here is the original template as well that we had specified.
这更或多或少是你期望它创建的提示。
In fact, if I print this out,
最后，让我们将此提示传递给LLM。
um, it realizes it has two input variables, style and text.
所以我要调用聊天，
Now let's specify the style.
我们之前设置的，
This is a style that I want the, uh,
作为OpenAI聊天GPT端点的参考。
customer message to be translated to.
如果我们打印出客户响应的内容，
So I'm gonna call this customer style.
那么它会给你返回，um，
And, uh, here's my same customer email as before.
这段文本是从英语海盗语翻译成礼貌的美式英语。
And now, if I create
当然，你可以想象其他使用情况，
customer messages, this will generate the prompt,
客户的电子邮件是其他语言，这也可以用来
and will pass this a large language model in a minute to get a response.
翻译消息，以便英语为母语的人理解并回复。
So if you want to look at the types,
我鼓励你暂停视频并运行代码，还可以
the customer message is actually a list.
尝试修改提示，看看是否可以获得不同的输出。
And, um, if you look at the first element of the list,
现在，让我们希望我们的客服代表
this is more or less that prompt that you would expect this to be creating.
用他们的原始语言回复客户。
Lastly, let's pass this prompt to the LLM.
所以，让我们假设英语为母语的客服代表写了这个并说，
So I'm gonna call chat,
嘿，客户，保修不包括，
which we had set earlier, um,
你的厨房清洁费，因为这是你的错，
as a reference to the OpenAI chat GPT endpoint.
你忘记盖上盖子，误用了你的搅拌机。
And if we print out the customer responses content,
很遗憾，再见。
then it gives you back, um,
不是很礼貌的消息，
this text translated from English Pirate to polite American English.
但是，让我们假设这是客服代表想要的。
And of course, you can imagine other use cases where
我们将指定
the customer emails are in other languages and this too can be used to
服务消息将被翻译成这种海盗风格。
translate the messages for an English-speaking to understand and reply to.
所以我们希望它以礼貌的语气用英语海盗语说话。
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code and also
因为我们之前创建了那个提示模板，
try modifying the prompt to see if you can get a different output.
很酷的是我们现在可以重复使用那个提示模板并指定
Now, let's hope our customer service agent
我们想要的输出样式是这个服务风格的海盗和这个服务回复的文本。
reply to the customer in their original language.
如果我们这样做，
So let's say English-speaking customer service agent writes this and say,
那就是提示。
hey there customer, warranty does not cover,
如果我们提示，
clean expenses for your kitchen because it's your fault,
聊天GPT，这是它给我们的回应。
that you misused your blender by forgetting to put on the lid.
啊，那里的伙计，我必须友好地告诉你，保修不包括
Tough luck, see ya.
你的厨房清洁费等等。
Not a very polite message,
是的，很遗憾，再见我的心爱的。
but, um, let's say this is what a customer service agent wants.
所以你可能会想知道为什么我们使用提示模板而不是，
We are going to specify that
你知道，只是一个F字符串？
the service message is going to be translated to this pirate style.
答案是，随着你构建复杂的应用程序，
So we want it to be in a polite tone that speaks in English Pirate.
提示可能会非常长和详细。
And because we previously created that prompt template,
因此，提示模板是一个有用的抽象，可以帮助您在可以重复使用好的提示时重复使用它们。
the cool thing is we can now reuse that prompt template and specify that
嗯，这是一个相对较长的提示示例，用于在线学习应用程序中对学生提交的作业进行评分。
the output style we want is this service style pirate and the text is this service reply.
像这样的提示可能会很长，您可以要求LLM首先解决问题，然后以特定格式输出。
And if we do that,
将其包装在Lanchain提示中可以更轻松地重用此类提示。
that's the prompt.
此外，您稍后会看到Lanchain为一些常见操作提供提示，
And if we prompt, um,
例如摘要或问题回答或连接到SQL数据库，
chat GPT, this is a response it gives us back.
或连接到不同的API。
Ahoy there matey, I must kindly inform you that the warranty be not covering
因此，通过使用一些Lanchain内置的提示，
the expenses or cleaning your galley and so on.
您可以快速使应用程序运行而无需自己设计提示。
Aye tough luck, farewell me hearty.
Lanchain提示库的另一个方面是它还支持输出解析，
So you might be wondering why are we using prompt templates instead of,
我们将在一分钟内介绍。
you know, just an F-string?
但是，当您使用LLM构建复杂应用程序时，
The answer is that as you build sophisticated applications,
通常会指示LLM以特定格式生成其输出，
prompts can be quite long and detailed.
例如使用特定关键字。
And so prompt templates are a useful abstraction to help you reuse good prompts when you can.
左侧的示例说明了使用LLM执行一种称为思维链推理的东西，
Um, this is an example of a relatively long prompt to
使用React框架。
grade a student's submission for an online learning application.
但是不要担心技术细节，
And a prompt like this can be quite long in which you can ask the LLM to first solve
但关键是LLM正在思考什么，
the problem and then have the output in a certain format and output in a certain format.
因为给LLM思考的空间，
And wrapping this in a Lanchain prompt makes it easier to reuse a prompt like this.
它通常可以得出更准确的结论。
Also, you see later that Lanchain provides prompts for some common operations,
然后将动作作为关键字执行特定操作，
such as summarization or question answering or connecting to SQL databases,
然后观察以显示从该操作中学到的内容，依此类推。
or connecting to different APIs.
如果您有一个提示，指示LLM使用这些特定关键字，
And so by using some of Lanchain's built-in prompts,
思考，动作和观察，
you can quickly get an application working without needing to,
那么这个提示可以与解析器配合使用，
um, engineer your own prompts.
以提取已标记为这些特定关键字的文本。
One other aspect of Lanchain's prompt libraries is that,
因此，这一起为指定LLM的输入提供了非常好的抽象，
it also supports output parsing,
然后还可以使用解析器正确解释LLM给出的输出。
which we'll get to in a minute.
因此，让我们回到使用Langchain的输出解析器的示例。
But when you're building a complex application using an LLM,
在这个例子中，让我们看一下如何使用LLM输出JSON，
you often instruct the LLM to generate its output in a certain format,
并使用Langchain解析该输出。
such as using specific keywords.
我将使用一个产品评论的运行示例来提取信息并以JSON格式格式化输出。
This example on the left illustrates using an LLM to carry out something called
这是一个期望的输出示例。
chain of thought reasoning using a framework called the React framework.
这实际上是一个Python字典，
But don't worry about the technical details,
其中产品是否为GIF，
but the keys of that is that the thought is what the LLM is thinking,
大规模的假，交付所需的天数为五天，
because by giving an LLM space to think,
价格值相当实惠。
it can often get some more accurate conclusions.
这是一个期望的输出示例。
Then action as a keyword to carry the specific action,
以下是客户评论以及尝试获得JSON输出的模板。
and then observation to show what it learned from that action, and so on.
以下是一个客户评论。
And if you have a prompt that instructs the LLM to use these specific keywords,
它说，睡眠吹风机非常惊人。
thought, action, and observation,
它有四个设置，蜡烛吹风机，
then this prompt can be coupled with a parser to extract out
温柔的微风，风城和龙卷风。
the text that has been tagged with these specific keywords.
它在两天内到达，正好是我妻子的周年礼物。
And so that together gives a very nice abstraction to specify the input to an LLM,
我认为我妻子非常喜欢它，她一言不发。
and then also have a parser correctly interpret the output that the LLM gives.
到目前为止，我是唯一使用它的人，等等。
And so with that, let's return to see an example of an output parser using Langchain.
以下是评论模板。
In this example, let's take a look at how you can have an LLM output JSON,
对于以下文本，提取以下信息，
and use Langchain to parse that output.
指定这是一个GIF。
And the running example that I'll use will be to extract information from
在这种情况下，是的，
a product review and format that output in a JSON format.
因为这是一个GIF。
So here's an example of how you would like the output to be formatted.
还有交付天数。
Technically, this is a Python dictionary,
需要多长时间才能交付？
where whether or not the product is a GIF,
看起来在这种情况下，它在两天内到达。
massive false, the number of days it took to deliver it was five,
还有，价格值是多少？
and the price value was pretty affordable.
比睡眠吹风机稍微贵一些，等等。
So this is one example of a desired output.
因此，评论模板要求LLM以客户评论作为输入，
Here is an example of,
并提取这三个字段，
um, customer review as well as a template to try to get to that JSON output.
然后将输出格式化为JSON，
So here's a customer review.
使用以下键。
It says, the sleep blower is pretty amazing.
好的。
It has four settings, candle blower,
以下是如何在Langchain中包装它。
gentle breeze, windy city, and tornado.
让我们导入聊天提示模板。
It arrived in two days just in time for my wife's anniversary present.
实际上我们之前已经导入过了。
I think my wife liked it so much she was speechless.
所以从技术上讲，这一行是多余的，
So far, I've been the only one using it, and so on.
但我会再次导入它，
Um, and here's a review template.
然后从上面的评论模板创建提示模板。
For the following text, extract the following information,
这是提示模板。
specify was this a GIF.
现在，类似于我们早期使用提示模板的方式，
So in this case, it would be yes,
让我们创建要传递给OpenAI端点的消息。
because this is a GIF.
创建OpenAI端点，调用该端点，然后让我们打印出响应。
Um, and also delivery days.
我鼓励您暂停视频并运行代码。
How long did it take to deliver?
然后就是这样了。
It looks like in this case, it arrived in two days.
它说GIF为true，交货时间为两天，
And, um, what's the price value?
价格值看起来也相当准确。
You know, slightly more expensive than the sleep blowers, and so on.
但请注意，如果我们检查响应的类型，
So the review template asks the LLM to take as input a customer review,
这实际上是一个字符串。
and extract these three fields,
看起来像JSON，看起来有键值对，
and then format the output as JSON,
但它实际上不是一个字典。
um, with the following keys.
这只是一个很长的字符串。
All right.
所以我真正想做的是去响应内容，
So here's how you can wrap this in line chain.
并从GIF键中获取值，这应该是true。
Let's import the chat prompt template.
但如果我运行这个，这应该会生成一个错误，因为，嗯，
We'd actually imported this already earlier.
这实际上是一个字符串，这不是一个Python字典。
So technically, this line is redundant,
所以让我们看看如何使用Langchain的解析器来做到这一点。
but I'll just import it again,
我将从Langchain导入响应模式和结构化输出解析器。
and then have the prompt templates, um,
并且，我将告诉它我想要解析什么，通过指定这些响应模式。
created from the review template up on top.
所以GIF模式被命名为GIF，
And so here's the prompt template.
这是描述。购买的物品是否作为礼物送给别人？回答true或yes，如果不是或未知，则为false等等。
And now, similar to our early usage of a prompt template,
所以我有一个GIF模式，
let's create the messages to pass to the OpenAI, uh, endpoint.
交货日期模式，价格值模式，
Create the OpenAI endpoint,
然后让我们将它们全部放入列表中。
call that endpoint, and then let's print out the response.
现在我已经指定了这些模式，
I encourage you to pause the video and run the code.
Langchain实际上可以直接给你提示，通过输出解析器告诉你要发送给LLM的指令。
And there it is.
通过输出解析器告诉你要发送给LLM的指令，这样，如果我要打印格式指令，
It says GIF is true, delivery days is two,
她有一套非常精确的LLM格式指令，可以生成输出，输出解析器可以处理。
and the price value also looks pretty accurate.
所以这是新的评论模板。
Um, but note that if we check the type of the response,
评论模板包括Langchain生成的格式指令，因此也可以从评论模板中创建提示，
this is actually a string.
然后创建将传递到OpenAI端点的消息。
So it looks like JSON and looks like it has key value pairs,
如果您想，您可以查看实际提示，
but it's actually not a dictionary.
它会告诉您如何提取字段，GIF、交货天数、价格值。
This is just one long string.
这是文本，这是格式化指令。
So what I'd really like to do is go to the response content,
最后，如果我们调用OpenAI端点，
and get the value from the GIF key, which should be true.
让我们看看我们得到了什么响应。
But I run this, this should generate an error because, well,
现在是这样的。
this is actually a string, this is not a Python dictionary.
现在，如果我们使用之前创建的输出解析器，
So let's see how we would use Langchain's,
您可以将其解析为输出字典。
um, parser in order to do this.
我们的打印应该是这样的。
I'm going to import response schema and structured output parser from Langchain.
请注意，这是字典类型，而不是字符串。
And, um, I'm going to tell it what I wanted to parse by specifying these response schemas.
这就是为什么我现在可以提取与GIFs键相关联的值并获得true，
So the GIF schema is named GIF,
或提取与交货天数相关联的值并获得2。
and here's the description.
或者您还可以提取与价格值相关联的值。
Was the item purchased as a gift for someone else?
因此，这是一种巧妙的方法，可以将您的LLM输出解析为Python字典，以使输出在下游处理中更容易使用。
Uh, answer true or yes,
我鼓励您暂停视频并运行代码。
false if not or unknown, and so on.
这就是模型、提示和解析器。
So have a GIF schema,
有了这些工具，希望您能轻松地重用自己的提示模板，
delivery day schema, price value schema,
与您合作的其他人分享提示模板，
and then let's put all three of them into a list as follows.
甚至使用Lanchain内置的提示模板，正如您刚才看到的，
Now that I've specified the schema for these, um,
这是一种巧妙的方法，可以将您的LLM输出解析为Python字典，以使输出在下游处理中更容易使用。
Langchain can actually give you the prompt itself, uh,
我鼓励您暂停视频并运行代码。
by having the output parser tell you what instructions it wants you to send to the LLM.
这就是模型、提示和解析器。
So if I were to print format instructions,
有了这些工具，希望您能轻松地重用自己的提示模板，
she has a pretty precise set of instructions for the LLM that will cause it to
与您合作的其他人分享提示模板，
generate an output that the output parser can process.
甚至使用Lanchain内置的提示模板，正如您刚才看到的，
So here's the new review template.
通常可以与输出解析器配对使用。
And the review template includes the format instructions that
这样，输入提示可以以特定格式输出，然后解析器将输出暂停以将数据存储在Python字典或其他数据结构中，以便于下游处理。
Langchain generated and so can create a prompt from the review template too,
我希望您在许多应用程序中都能找到这个有用。
and then create the messages that will pass to the OpenAI endpoint.
有了这个，让我们进入下一个视频，看看Lanchain如何帮助您构建更好的聊天机器人或使LLM的聊天更有效，
If you want, you can take a look at the actual prompt,
通过更好地管理它到目前为止所记住的对话。
which gives you instructions to extract the fields,